Register of the Robert Daniel Murphy papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Photographs II, 1900-1976
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy sitting across the table with an unidentified individual, 1958, and 3 prints depicting Robert Murphy with the NATO delegation guests (Karl Le Compte, Jacques de Menditte of France, A.C. Normann of Denmark, Johm Seitlinger of France, Giuseppe M. Sibille of Italy, and Fridjon Thordarson of Iceland) at a dinner in their honor, Washington, D.C., 1958 January 6 (Box-folder 192: 12)
  - 3 prints of Robert Murphy with Herbert Hoover and Queen Elizabeth, 1958 June, and 9 prints depicting Robert Murphy talking to others and greeting someone, 1958 June 19
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy with William Farrell at MATS before he left for Beirut, Lebanon, 1958 July 16
  - 2 prints depicting Robert Murphy and President Dwight D. Eisenhower after his return from a trip to the Middle East, 1958 August 13
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Louis Mountbatten, A. C. Wedemeyer, and others sitting for a group photo, 1958 October 16, and 2 prints of Polish parliamentarians, 1958 October 17 (Box-folder 192: 13)
  - 12 prints of Robert Murphy with Ambassador Luce, Ambassador Zellerbach, and others at Ciampine Airport, Rome and at St. Peter's Basilica, Vatican City, on the occasion of the Coronation of Pope John XXIII, 1958 November 3-5
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy and James A. Farrell at the opening session of the forty-fifth National Foreign Trade Convention, 1958 December (Box-folder 192: 13)
  - 6 prints depicting Robert Murphy with others at an American Committee on Italian Migration dinner, 1958 December 20 (Box-folder 192: 14)
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy with Japanese ambassador Kaichiro Asakai, 1959 January 14
  - 18 prints, including 6 depicting Robert Murphy with President Dwight D. Eisenhower, Harris Ellsworth, William P. Rogers, and others at a luncheon honoring Ernest Marples, postmaster general of Great Britain, 1959 January 14; 4 prints depicting Robert Murphy and others holding certificates; and 8 prints depicting President Dwight D. Eisenhower with John Foster Dulles, Harris Ellsworth, John A. McGone and Wernher von Braun, 1959 January 20(?)
  - 4 prints depicting Robert Murphy and others during the visit of Ahmadou Ahidjo, prime minister of Cameroon, 1959 March 16
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy at Saint Joseph's College, on the occasion of the award of degree of doctor of laws, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1959 June 7
  - 4 prints depicting Kimberley Knoll, Dorothy(?) Bess Demaree, and a Chinese individual, including 2 prints taken in front of the American embassy in Moscow, 1959 October (Box-folder 193: 1)
  - 1 print depicting Bess Demaree riding a rickshaw pulled by a man in Asheville, North Carolina, 1962 November
  - 1 album of 22 prints depicting Robert Murphy on the occasion of his visit to the National Security Agency fifth annual Security Week, 1966 September 23
  - 2 prints depicting Robert Murphy with students and others in a program, "Youth Wants to Know,", 1967 January 3
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with Morarji Desai, prime minister and minister of finance, India, on the occasion of the Far East-America Council's luncheon in his honor, 1967 September 14
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with W. E. Knox and Mrs. Watanabe, luncheon, Far East–America Council's Conference on Asia, 1967 October 5
  - 2 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Sterling Brown, Margaret Truman Daniels, and Charles Evans Hughes III, 1967 November 12 (Box-folder 193: 2)
  - 4 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Samuel D. Leidesdorf, Mitch Miller, and others at the annual meeting of the Board of Trustees, 1967 November 13
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy at the Far East-America Council dinner for the prime minister of Japan, Eisaku Sato, 1967 November 16
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy with others in a group photo on the occasion of William E. Knox's 21st annual pre-Christmas luncheon, 1967 December 15
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy congratulating John Gardner and Lewis L. Strauss, recipients of the Hughes awards for distinguished governmental service, 1968, and 1 print of Robert Murphy with Cuthbert E. Allen, Brian J. Egan, and Jaroslav Pelikan at the National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box-folder 193: 3)
  - 4 prints of Robert Murphy with Sterling W. Brown, R. C. Kirkwood, Harold M. Lane, Samuel D. Leidesdorf, Sam Levonson, and Meshulam Riklis at a department store dinner, New York, 1968 May 8
  - 3 prints of Robert Murphy with Fred R. Esty and Dean Rusk, U. B. Wanninayake, and Oliver Weerasinghe at the Far East–America Council Conference on Asia luncheon, 1968 October 7
  - 2 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Sterling Brown, Jaroslav Celikan, Brian Egan, Lewis Strauss and Oscar Strauss II, annual meeting of the Board of Trustees, Charles Evans Hughes award dinner, National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1968 November 17
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy sharing a joke with Jackie Robinson, who receives a National Conference of Christians and Jews Special Service Award at the annual meeting of the NCCJ's Board of Governors, New York, 1969 (Box-folder 193: 4)
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy presenting President Richard Nixon a Steuben glass horse head at the Kentucky Derby, 1969
  - 1 print from David Hyatt depicting Robert Murphy and others, National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1969 January 6(?)
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy and Lucius(?) D. Clay, International Rescue Committee dinner, New York, 1969 February 24
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy attending a luncheon given by the Far East-America Council in honor of Choong-Hoon Park, deputy prime minister of Korea, 1969 April 25
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with unidentified individuals, 1970 (Box-folder 193: 5)
  - 2 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Fred R. Esty, James A. Farley, Chiang Ching-kuo, and Walter McConaughy at the Far East-America Council luncheon in honor of Chiang Ching-kuo, vice premier of the Republic of China, 1970 April 24
  - 1 print depicting the Kimberley Knolls with the Duke of Windsor, 1970 Spring (Box-folder 193: 6)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy at the front door of the Corning Glass Center as the Duke of Windsor departs, 1970 June(?)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with Faisal ibn Abdul-Aziz, king of Saudi Arabia, at his residence, 1970 September 8
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy with Ismail Bin Dato Abdul Rahman, deputy prime minister of Malaysia, at the Far East-America luncheon in his honor, 1970 October 27
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy in a group photograph of William E. Knox's 24th annual pre-Christmas luncheon, 1970 December 11 (Box-folder 193: 7)
  - 4 prints depicting Robert Murphy with unidentified individuals, 1971 (Box-folder 193: 8)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with Amory Houghton, Jr., 1971
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with Harald Graf v. Posadowsky Wehner, German consul general, 1971
  - 1 print of Paulette Borel given to Robert Murphy as a souvenir of the Allied landing in North Africa, 1971 February 25
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy and President Richard Nixon, 1971 April 15
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy with an unidentified individual, American-Arab Association for Commerce & Industry, 1971 April 23 (Box-folder 193: 9)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy with unidentified individuals, 1971 April 26(?)
  - 2 prints of Robert Murphy with Sterling Brown, Lewis L. Strauss, and Oscar Strauss, annual meeting of the Board of Trustees, National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1971 November 17
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy in golf cart watching Marshall Green pitch at Chevy Chase Country Club, 1971 December 12
  - 3 prints depicting Robert Murphy with John A. Coleman, William H. Donaldson, Alan Greenspan, Frederick A. Klingenstein, Joseph A. Klingenstein, Bernard J. Laskar, James J. Needham, Ellmore C. Patterson, James M. Roche, and John C. Stone, 1972 (Box-folder 193: 10)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with Loy Henderson, 1972 July(?)
  - 8 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Henri Bertrand and others at the celebration of the 30th anniversary of the landing of Allied troops in North Africa, Hotel de Ville, Paris, 1972 November 8
  - 14 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Sterling Brown, George Christopher, David Hyatt, Oscar Lazarus, Jerome Randolph, Arthur Rubloff, Oscar S. Strauss II, and others honoring Jerome H. Holland with the National Conference of Christians and Jews Eighth Charles Evans Hughes Award for "courageous leadership in governmental service," New York, 1972 November 19-20 (Box-folder 193: 11)
  - 3 prints, one each of Robert Murphy, Herbert Brownell, and Sarah Houghton, 1973(?) (Box-folder 194: 1)
  - 1 print depicting Robert Murphy and others at the meeting of the Commission on Organization of Government Conduct of Foreign Policy, Lyndon Baines Johnson Room, U.S. Capitol, 1973 April 16
  - 3 prints, including 2 of Mrs. Robert D. Murphy and 1 print of Maya Ba and Johnny Cash taken the night before their Christmas wedding, 1973 December
  - 12 prints depicting Robert Murphy and others talking, sitting around a table, and wearing orange jackets and vests, 1974(?) (Box-folder 194: 2)
  - 3 prints depicting Robert Murphy with Mr. and Mrs. Louis Kissinger, 1974(?)
  - 3 prints of Robert Murphy with others, 1974
  - 1 album of 38 prints, United States Military Academy, 1974 April-May (Box-folder 194: 3)
  - 2 prints depicting Robert Murphy, James A. Farley, Peter Cross, and Theodore M. Hesburgh at the Laetare Medal award dinner, 1974 May 16 (Box-folder 194: 4)
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy cutting his birthday cake, 1974 October 27
  - 1 print of Robert Murphy with Fred R. Esty, Conference on Asia, 1975 September 8 (Box-folder 194: 5)
  - 1 print of an unidentified individual, 1976 March 8
  - 1 print of Mrs. Robert Murphy, 1976 December 3
  - 7 prints depicting Robert Murphy, taken by the United States Army, 1976 December 3
- Increment, 1949-1952
  Scrapbooks containing photographs and clippings, and photo album
  - Scrapbooks, 1949-1952
    Scrapbooks containing photographs and clippings (originally housed in 3-ring binders)
    - Binder number 2, December 1949 - May 1950 (Box-folder 194: 6)
    - Binder number 4, August - October 1950 (Box-folder 195: 1)
    - Binder number 6, December 1950 - February 1951 (Box-folder 195: 2)
    - Binder number 7, March - May 1951 (Box-folder 195: 3)
    - Binder number 8, May - July 1951 (Box-folder 195: 4)
    - Binder number 10, January - March 1952 (Box-folder 196: 1)
  - Photo album, 26 June 1951
- Declassified U.S. government records, 1944-1971
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled records determined by the government to be unclassified. Includes materials from the original acquisition (described separately) and the incremental materials. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover
  - 2010 release of record, 1954 January 13 (Reading room workstation)
    Text of Murphy speech at the National War College, "Influence of politics upon military operations: Operation Torch." Available as PDF file. The PDF file consists of page images, so full-text search is not possible
  - 2011 July release of records, 1944-1971
    - Unclassified materials, 1954 1970-1971 (Box-folder 196: 3)
      United Nations General Assembly resolutions, Corning Glass cables, note and classified material receipt
    - Murphy speech at Naval War College, 1954 June 8 (Box-folder 196: 4)
      Includes related correspondence
    - Murphy speech at Naval War College, "The International Scene", 1954 August 23 (Box-folder 196: 5)
    - Murphy speech at Naval War College, 1956 August 20 (Box-folder 196: 6)
    - Murphy speech at Naval War College, 1957 August 26 (Box-folder 196: 7)
    - Murphy speech at Air Force Scientific Advisory Board, 1957 December 4 (Box-folder 196: 8)
    - General agreement on tariffs and trade file, 1968 (Box-folder 196: 9)
    - Ambassadorships file, 1955, 1968 (Box-folder 196: 10)
    - Personal files
      Filed by the first letter of the surname of correspondent
      - A-N, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 196: 11)
      - O-Z, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 196: 12)
      - A-K, 1946 (Box-folder 196: 13)
      - L-P, 1946 (Box-folder 196: 14)
      - Q-Z, 1946 (Box-folder 197: 1)
      - A-Z, 1947 (Box-folder 197: 2)
      - A-Z, 1948 (Box-folder 197: 3)
    - Memorandum of conversation regarding preparation for Council of Foreign Ministers (CFM), 1949 (Box-folder 197: 4)
    - Miscellaneous papers preparatory to CFM, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 5)
    - Paris CFM German unity file, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 6)
      Consists of U.S. delegation working papers
    - Paris CFM Germany file, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 7)
    - Paris CFM miscellaneous file, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 8)
    - Paris CFM file, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 9)
      Consists of excerpts from U.S. delegation minutes
    - Minutes and agenda Paris CFM, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 10)
      Consists of U.S. minutes of plenary, restricted and private meetings
    - Quai D'Orsay minutes and memos of conversation, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 11)
    - Paris CFM U.S. delegation staff meeting minutes, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 12)
    - Memoranda for Mr. Murphy, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 13)
      In English and French
    - Program for Germany file, 1949 (Box-folder 197: 14)
  - 2017 release of records, 1924-1973 (Reading room workstation)
  - 2018 release of records, 1954-1970 (Reading room workstation)